<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop I: The Command Line &amp; Git on </title>
    <link>https://doks.netlify.app/docs/workshop-i/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshop I: The Command Line &amp; Git on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doks.netlify.app/docs/workshop-i/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisite Activities</title>
      <link>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/prerequisite-activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/prerequisite-activities/</guid>
      <description>Read # The Schism at the Heart of the Open-Source Movement by Sidney Fussell
Do #  For those using Apple devices: You can make the installation of the following list very quick and easy by first installing Homebrew. Search &amp;ldquo;terminal&amp;rdquo; using Spotlight or in Finder, open the application, then paste the command featured centerally on the linked webpage (hit the little clipboard beside it) and hit enter! I will provide the installation commands for each item listed below that you can enter into the terminal after installing Homebrew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working in the Command Line</title>
      <link>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/working-in-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/working-in-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>Command Line Basics #    Mac &amp;amp; Linux Windows Powershell Use     cd [path_to_file] cd [path_to_file] change directory&amp;ndash; go to a different folder on your computer (hint: to go back a step type ..)   ls ls list all the files in the folder you&amp;rsquo;re currently in   pwd pwd print working directory&amp;ndash; if you forget what folder you&amp;rsquo;re in, type this and the command line will tell you where you are   mkdir [folder] mkdir [folder] Creates a new directory (aka folder) in the directory you&amp;rsquo;re in   man [command] help [command] Tells you what a command does by outputting the documentation for it    Keyboard Shortcuts for the Command Line #    Command Use     ctrl + c Cancels the command that is currently running, meaning that the command will stop whatever it&amp;rsquo;s doing immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Reference</title>
      <link>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/markdown-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/markdown-reference/</guid>
      <description>More information on Markdown can be found here.
  Styling Markdown   Headings  # H1 ## H2 ### H3    Bold **bold text**   Italic *italicized text*   Blockquote  Quotation   Ordered list  1. First item 2. Second item 3. Third item    Bullets  - First item - Second item - Third item    Task list  - [x] Write the press release - [ ] Update the website - [ ] Contact the media    Definition list  term : definition    Code `one line of code`   Code block  ``` { &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/connecting-git-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/connecting-git-and-github/</guid>
      <description>So GitHub knows that your personal device can be trusted, you must generate a SSH (Secure Shell) key for your device which will then be added to your GitHub account so that you may upload and modify your work from your desktop.
👉  Windows Users: To configure Git and perform the initial set up of GitHub on your device, you must use Git Bash which is located under the Git folder that can be accessed from the Start menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pushing to GitHub &amp; Static Site Resources</title>
      <link>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/pushing-to-github-static-site-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doks.netlify.app/workshop-i/pushing-to-github-static-site-resources/</guid>
      <description>Using Git # Creating a repository and adding it to Github # After going on to GitHub and creating a new repository by hitting the &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; symbol in the upper right corner:
 To create the README file (which you can modify later): echo &amp;quot;# [your_project_name]&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; README.md Initialize your folder as a git repository (aka to be tracked with git): git init git add -A git commit -m &amp;quot;first commit&amp;quot; git branch -M main git remote add origin [link to your repository on github] git push -u origin main  Updating your repository following its creation # 👉  If you are working in a repo that has multiple users, your first command before should be git pull so that the repository on your computer receives any changes made by other users!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
